### **Charles Tucker Barrett**

ctbarrett.tech@gmail.com | 919-999-7792 | Raleigh, NC | 27540

Website: https://tucker.tech

GitHub: https://github.com/GrinninBarrett | LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/tucker-barrett

### Summary

Full stack web developer with a background in music education. Experienced working on collaborative teams, spontaneous problem-solving, and devising creative approaches to difficult situations. Interested in leveraging my technical and artistic experience to solve real-world problems to make our planet a better place. Possess a Full Stack Web Development certificate and have a genuine love for technology and the arts.

#### Technical Skills

Git/GitHub, Agile, JavaScript, ¡Query, MongoDB, Express, React, Node.js, GraphQL, MySQL, JSON, HTML, CSS

## **Projects**

CoinBull | Contributing Developer | https://coinbullapp.herokuapp.com/

- ◆ Full stack web application to track cryptocurrency information | MERN stack, GraphQL, Heroku
- ♦ Repo: https://github.com/GrinninBarrett/CoinBull

Book Search Engine | Sole Developer | https://glacial-stream-35332.herokuapp.com/

- ◆ Full stack web application to search for and save books | MERN stack, GraphQL, Heroku
- Repo: https://github.com/GrinninBarrett/book-search-engine

Skillet & Shaker | Contributing Developer | https://grinninbarrett.github.io/recipe-finder

- ♦ Uses recipe APIs to find food and drink recipes based on user criteria | JavaScript, HTML, and CSS
- ◆ Repo: https://github.com/grinninbarrett/recipe-finder

Etch-a-Sketch | Sole Developer | https://grinninbarrett.github.io/etch-a-sketch

- ♦ Drawing canvas based on the famous Etch-a-Sketch | JavaScript, HTML, and CSS
- Repo: https://github.com/grinninbarrett/etch-a-sketch

#### Experience

Apple - Specialist - October 2021 - present

♦ Utilize thorough product knowledge to provide personalized solutions for new Apple product owners

VIPKid, Online Teaching Platform - ESL Teacher - 2018 - present

- ♦ Maintain a nearly 100% rebooking rate 100% 5/5 star-rated teacher in the past year
- ♦ Manage relationships with students and parents, building strong rapport

South Harnett Elementary School, Bunnlevel, NC - Music Teacher - 2019 - 2021

- ♦ Developed a comprehensive, sequential music curriculum for grades 3-5 and K-5 special needs
- ◆ Planned and executed successful performances, ensuring students' personal and musical growth

Worwick Franklin Institute, Ulsan, South Korea - Homeroom Kindergarten Teacher - 2015 - 2018

- ♦ Contributed to a nearly 200% increase in enrollment after my first year
- Bridged language and cultural divides to collaborate with Korean coworkers

#### Leadership / Honors

- President, Phi Mu Alpha Sinfonia, Delta Sigma Chapter, Columbia, SC 2010 2011
- ♦ Drum Major, USC Marching Band, Columbia, SC 2009 2010
- ♦ Eagle Scout, Boy Scouts of America, Troop 222, Abingdon, VA

# Certificates

- ♦ Introduction to Computer Science and Programming Using Python, MITx
- ◆ FreeCodeCamp Responsive Web Design

#### Education

University of North Carolina - Chapel Hill, Chapel Hill, NC - 2021

Certificate - JavaScript Full Stack Web Development

University of South Carolina, Columbia, SC - 2012

Bachelor of Music Education with Horn Performance Certificate